Day after day, I awake in a daze,
mezamete ha kurikaesu nemui asa ha
目覚めては繰り返す　眠い朝は
And fasten my collar tightly.
eri no tai wo kitsuku shime
襟のタイをきつく締め
As I walk through the door to my classroom,
kyoushitsu no doa kuguru to hon no sukoshi
教室のドアくぐるとほんの少し
I have the slightest bit of pride.
mune wo hatte arukidaseru
胸を張って歩き出せる
Then a wind rushed through that normal, everyday life.
sonna nichijou ni fukinukeru kaze
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
I have a feeling I can hear it,
kikoeta ki ga shita
聞こえた気がした
I have a feeling I can sense it,
kanjita ki ga shitanda
感じた気がしたんだ
Beginning to tremble within my chest.
furuedasu ima kono mune de
震え出す今この胸で
I have a feeling it's on its way,
mou kuru ki ga shita
もう来る気がした
As the millions of stars began to disappear,
ikuoku no hoshi ga kiesatteku no wo
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
I sent them on their way,
miokutta
見送った
Waving my hand,
te wo futta
手を振った
Whispering, "Congratulations".
yokatta ne, to
よかったね、と
Incinerator
So, how should we begin?
それで何から始めるの
I've thought about it a lot, and I think we should start with Yui first.
すげー悩んだんだけどさ
最初はユイがいいかと思う
だれ
Who?
You know. She's the one who was singing in the band during the guerilla-style concert.
ほら　大食堂のゲリラライブで
バンドのボーカルをやってたやつ
You don't remember her?
覚えてないか
Oh.
ああ
あいつ　いつも元気でさ
She's always so full of energy,
teasing Hinata while she laughs along.
日向いじめて笑ってるしさ
She's performed in the band, too,
バンドボーカルもやって
やりたいことやってさ
so I think she's done plenty enough to feel fulfilled.
もう十分報われてるんじゃないかって思うんだ
後はほんの一押し
All she needs is a push.
背中を押してやれば
Just a little push to her back, and she'll be able to get out of here.
あいつはここから出ていける
That's what I think.
そんな気がするんだ
Then I suppose that's good.
そう思うんなら　いいんじゃない
賛成か
So you agree with me?
よし　じゃそうしよう
Okay, then let's do this.
で　そっちの首尾はどうだ
So, how are things going on your end?
Well, it took some time to finish.
まあ　時間はかかったけど
「ハンドソニック」バージョン５
Hand Sonic: Version 5.
Here is Hand Sonic Version 5.
これが「ハンドソニック」バージョン５
天使っつうか　悪魔のようだな
It's less angelic... and more devilish.
You asked me to make it look diabolic since I'm supposed to be evil, so this is what it became... Is it not good?
あなたが冷酷な天使なのだから
まがまがしくと言ったから　こんな感じに
だめ
Oh no, it's perfect. It's got a really bad feel about it.
いや　いいよ　すげー嫌な感じだ
嫌って
"Bad feel"?
いやいやいや　いいよ　すごくいい
I mean, it's great! Just perfect.
Oh, and do you think you can grow wings?
あっ　あと羽生えねぇかな
Wings? What for?
羽？
生やしてどうするの
いや　見た目かっちょいいじゃん
I mean, for awesome visual effect.
かっちょいいのがいいの
You like it "awesome"?
Well, I just thought it'd be more angel-like.
いや　その方が天使らしいかなって
考えておく
I'll think about it.
Thanks.
よろしく
So, what should I do?
で　私はどうしたらいいの
O-Oh. Right.
あっ　ああ　そうだった
こうしよう
Let's do this. You'll show up during her band practice.
おまえはあいつのバンド練習中に現れるんだ
そしてこう言う
When you do, say this:
「他の文化部から騒音の苦情が出ている」
"Other clubs are filing claims over the racket."
そして　ユイを指してこう言うんだ
Then point at Yui and say, "Your guitar is especially bad."
「特におまえのギターがひどい」
「おまえのせいでバンドが死んでいる」
"You're killing the band."
"As such, I will be confiscating that guitar for a while."
「なので暫くそのギターは没収させてもらう」
そしてユイのギターを取り上げて　おまえはその場を立ち去る
Then you'll take Yui's guitar and run off.
もちろん　ユイは追って来る
Of course, Yui will chase you, but you'll be running.
おまえは逃げる
From there, just make your way over to the courtyard.
そして中庭まで来てくれ
そこで俺がおまえにぶつかるふりをする
When you get there, I'll pretend to bump into you.
おまえは同時にギターを手放せ
You'll drop the guitar at that point, and I'll catch it. You just keep running away.
俺が受け取るから　そのまま逃げろ
It'll create a situation where I can be alone with her.
そうしてあいつと二人っきりになれる状況を作ってくれ
Okay.
分かった
All right. Let's begin when their practice starts!
よし
じゃあ　練習の始まる頃を見計らってゴーだ
Let's go start a revolution, let's go make our dreams come true.
kakumei wo okoshi ni ikou yume wo kanae ni ikou
革命を起こしにいこう　夢を叶えにいこう
Unused Room
Classroom Building A
If we break into a sprint, we can go anywhere we like,
kakedashitara doko mademo ikou
駆け出したらどこまでもいこう
Stop!
Einstein's...
ainshutain no...
アインシュタインの...
ストップ
Come on, Yui! Don't sing with such poor rhythm.
こら　ユイ
そんなよれよれなリズムで続けるな
えぇぇっ
Yui, maybe you should focus on either singing or playing.
ユイ　歌うか弾くかどっちかに専念した方がいいんじゃないの
Yeah, that's so true. They both sound horrendous right now.
ああ　そりゃあ言えてる
今のまんまじゃあ　ひど過ぎるわ
What? But Iwasawa-san sang while she played.
そんな
岩沢さん　弾きながら歌ってましたよ
Yeah, since she was good at both.
それは岩沢はどっちもうまかったからだよ
わたしだって頑張ってますよ
I'm trying my best, you know.
みんな言う事キツすぎますよ
You're all too harsh!
The concerts are always packed, too.
ライブだって　ちゃんと盛り上がってるじゃないですか
But this time, we'll be releasing a new song.
でも　今回は新曲だぜ
Tenshi?!
天使
おまえのギターのせいでバンドが死んでいる
Your guitar performance is killing the band.
一瞬にして今のバンドの弱点を見抜いた
She pointed out the current band's weakness instantly!
やっぱりただものじゃない
I knew she was special!
音が分かるのよ
She can tell the notes.
No way! I thought you wouldn't notice!
そんな
皆は気付いていないと思ってたのに
というわけで　暫くそのギターは没収させてもらう
As such, I will be confiscating that guitar for a while.
Hey, Yui!
あっ　ちょっと　ユイ
大丈夫か
Are you all right?
はい
Here.
Why are you alone?
なぜおまえ一人なんだ
Because she didn't chase after me.
追って来なかったから
えッ
Shine Days
そうそう　ギター無しじゃ全然よれないじゃん
There. You're perfect without the guitar.
But there's not enough jam to it.
でも　サウンドが薄っぺらくないですか
We need a rhythm guitar in there.
リズムギター要るっしょ
Then how about adding another side guitarist instead?
じゃあ　サイドギターもう一人入れようか
My point is...
あたしが言いたいのは
やっぱバンドはボーカルがギター背負って歌うのが
It looks best visually when the vocalist sings and plays the guitar at the same time, damn it!
一番絵面的に痺れんでしょって話じゃ
ごらっ
わーっ　こいつひさ子さんにキレた
She just lost it with Hisako-san!
I'm gonna go get my guitar back!
やっぱ　ギター取り返してくる
やばっ
Crap!
Hey! Damn it, Yui!
な　おい　こら　ユイ
Here she comes!
来るぞ
Where did she go?
どこ行った
There she is!
わっいた
Wait!
ん待て
あッ　わりぃ
Oops, sorry!
わぁ
ばっ、ばか　高過ぎ
You idiot, that's too high!
My guitar!
あたしのギター
Don't worry, it's fine.
大丈夫　無事だよ
先輩が守ってくれたんですねぇ　天使から
You rescued it from Tenshi for me?!
あっ　あいつはどこだ　こらーー
Where the hell did she go?!
Hey, now. No need to get so angry.
ったく　なにが「こら」だ
相変わらずおまえ　好き放題やってるな
You're really doing whatever you want, aren't you?
えッ　好き放題？
Huh? Whatever I want? No, I'm not.
やってないよ好き放題なんて
バンドのボーカルの座を射止めたじゃん
Well, you've got the vocal position in the band, and you're even playing the guitar.
ギターまで弾いてさ
This is nothing. It's only one of the many things that I've wanted to do.
そんなの全然だよ
やりたかったことの一つに過ぎないよ
Huh? There are more?
えッ　他にもあるのか
Yeah, a lot.
あるよ　いっぱい
A lot... Then-
いっぱいって
いや待て
Actually, wait, let's change tack.
じゃあ　場所変えるよ
So, what else is on your list?
で　他にはなんだよ
Front of the School Cafeteria
話さなきゃいけないの
Do I need to share them for some reason?
Not if you don't want to.
話したくなかったらいいけどさ
いいよ 話してあげる
It's fine. I'll tell you.
I've got lots of things I want to do, more than others do.
あたしねぇ　やりたいこと人よりいっぱいあるんだ
どうしてだと思う
Why do you think that is?
Well, isn't it because you couldn't do them when you were alive?
そりゃ　あれだろう
生きてる時にできなかったからだろう
Yup, that's exactly right.
そうそう
その通り
小さい時にさ　後ろから車に撥ねられちゃってさ
I got hit by a car from behind when I was little.
That's how I became paralysed.
それでさ　体動かなくなっちゃった
I was totally bedridden.
完全に寝たきりだったんだよねぇ
もう介護なしに生きてならないの
I couldn't live without others taking care of me.
お母さんに頼り切りだった
I was completely dependent on Mum.
お母さんにすごく悪いことしたなって
I felt so bad for her.
テレビだけは見れたからさ
But I was able to watch TV, so I watched music channels, saw bands play, and started wishing I could do the same.
音楽番組でバンド見て
こういうのを自分でできたらいいなって思って
I see. Then I'm happy for you right now.
そうか
じゃあよかったじゃん
Yup!
うん
So, what else do you want to do?
で　あとやりたいことは何だ
Well, I used to watch the baseball broadcasts, too.
うん　野球中継もねぇ　よく見てたんだ
野球だったら　球技大会でやってただろう
If it's baseball, you did that on Ball Day.
But I couldn't get a single one that day!
その時打ってなかったじゃん
A hit?
ヒット？
ホームラン
I mean a home run!
Huh?! And you have to hit one of those?
はぁ　それは何　打たねぇとだめなの
Of course I have to.
だめだねぇ
バントの方がもっとうまくなったら
Once I get better in the band,
I plan on practising baseball, too.
ちゃんと野球の練習もしようと思ってるんだけどねぇ
その両立はかなり大変だ
Balancing those two will be difficult...
Let me ask, just in case: Are there other things?
一応聞いておこう　他には
Soccer.
サッカー
Soccer?
サッカー？
It was so popular.
ブームだったじゃん
いや　確かにそうだったかもしれんが
Yeah, it might have been, but...
You've got too many interests!
多趣味すぎだ
Who in the world would try to be in a band, play baseball, and play soccer at the same time?
どこの世界に
バントと野球とサッカーを一緒にしようなんてやつがいる
You wouldn't have more, would you?
まさかまだ有ったりは
プロレスかな
Wrestling!
This makes no sense.
訳が分からない
どこの世界に
Who in the world would...
Well, I guess she just wants to do all the things she saw on TV.
っつうか　テレビで見たものばかりに憧れてんだなぁ
しかし　これは大変だぞ
Still, it's going to be a pain to make sure everything she listed comes true.
今聞いたすべてを叶えてやるなんて
Okay! I'll grant those wishes!
分かった
俺が叶えてやる
まずは　ええと
First off, um... why don't we start with the easiest one? Wrestling, that is.
手軽なとこから
プロレスから行って見っか
Wrestling? Really?
プロレス
技は
Which move?
German Suplex!
ジャーマンスープレックス
German suplex
I-I can't do something that elaborate!
ジャッ　そんな派手な技ができるか
Choose something more doable, like a joint lock.
関節技とかできそうなのにしろよ
But I love the German Suplex.
だって憧れだったんだもの　ジャーマンスープレックス
German suplex
And imagine pinning down the game just like that.
しかも　そのままホールド勝ち
Don't say such a scary thing with such a cute voice!
そんな　おちゃめに物騒なことを言うな
ああ　オーケー
Okay, fine. Give it a try.
じゃ　やって見ろよ
I can?
いいの
Yeah.
ああ
All right!
よっしゃーーッ
Here I go...!
Whoa...
おまえ思ったより力あるじゃん
You're stronger than I'd thought!
Go on, finish it!
行ける行ける
いってー
Ow!
I guess a girl like me can't do it.
やっぱり女の子の私なんかには無理かなぁ
いや　できそうでしたよ　むっちゃ惜しかったですよ
Yes, you can! You almost had it there!
えっ　そう？
Oh, really?
Then can I try it again?
じゃもう一回やっていい
Huh? S-Sure, but can we do this on the grass?
ああ　とりあえず下が芝な所に行っていいか
I'll die otherwise.
俺が死ぬ
アハハ　死ぬかっつうの
Why would you?
No, it wasn't a joke...
いや　ジョークじゃないんだが
Enough, already.
持たない
すみません
Please! I'll do it right next time!
次はできますから
本当最後だからなぁ
This seriously will be the last time, okay?
I'm heading back.
もう帰る
先輩
Senpai!
おまえさ　もしかしてブリッジとかできないじゃないの
Let me guess. You can't do a bridge, can you?
I can, too!
できますよ
Show me.
やって見ろよ
あれッ
Huh?
やっぱり原因はこれだったのか
I knew this was why.
I nearly passed out several times because of this...
このために　俺は無駄に何度も気を失いかけたのか
まずはブリッジの特訓だな
You need to work on getting the bridge down first.
Boo! That's boring.
ああん　つまんない
Just do it!
いいから　やれ
セーノッ
Ready, set...
ほら　頑張れ
Come on. Higher.
だめだろう　こら
Don't give up!
But I've never done a position like that!
だって　こんな格好したことないんだもん
If you can't do it, then you can't do a German Suplex, either.
でもできなきゃジャーマンスープレックスできなぇぞ
German suplex
頑張ります
I'll try...
Several Hours Later
-数小时后-
できてます　よんで
I... have it down... right...?
ぶるぶる震えてるんが
You're trembling, but I guess that's fine.
まあ　いいか
じゃ　行きますよ
All right. Here I go!
Bring it on!
こい
おっ　腕はお腹にしっかり回ったままだ
Her arms are locked good around my waist. There's no way for me to get out of this!
これは逃げようがない
It's perfect!
It's a perfect... German Suplex!
完璧だ　完璧だ
ジャーマンスープレックスだ
German suplex
One. Two. Three.
ワン　ツー　スリー　カンカンカン　試合終了
Gong! Gong! Gong!
Game set!
やった
I did it! I did it!
やったんだ私
やったー　万歳！！
Yay! Whee!
Yay! Yay! Yay!
How many more of these do I have to go through?
やった…もう　やった
こんなのがあといくつ続くんだ
Yay!
How about we take care of soccer next?
次はサッカーにすっか
Hallway
Classroom Building
A one-on-one PK game good enough?
一対一のピーケーでいいよな
No, I wanna dribble past five people and score the goal.
いやだよ　五人抜きのドリブルシュートじゃなきゃ
マラドーナだよ
That's what Maradona did.
いや　知っているけどさ
Yes, I know.
ああっ　分かった
Fine! Leave it to me!
まかしとけ
お－い　ＴＫ
Hey, T.K., do you know where Matsushita Fifth is?
松下五段知らないか
今のやつ　俺のように踊れない
Right now, he can't dance like I can.
Don't let me cry!
I'm sure he couldn't. So, where is he?
そりゃあそうだろうな
で
山籠もり
Training. In the mountains.
Training in the mountains? Well that's pretty far away from dancing.
山籠もり？
またダンスとは正反対な所に行ったなぁ
じゃあ　暫く帰って来ないのか
So he won't return for a while?
じゃ、まあ　あんたでいいや
Whatever. I'll ask you.
今から俺の言うメンバーを集めてもらえるか
Can you get together the people I tell you to right now?
Don't tell Yuri, but I got this letter from Tenshi.
ゆりには内緒だが
Men's Room
Classroom Building C
天使からこんな手紙が
"How ridiculous to call yourselves men, when you can't even beat one girl."
女一人にも歯が立たぬのに
男を名乗るとは片腹痛し
おーッ　「片腹痛し」なんてよく読めたな
You actually read "ridiculous" correctly.
Was the dumbass cured?
アホが治ったか
Even a dumbass can read it.
いや　アホでも読めるよ
スポーツマンシップに則り
"I shall correct your sissy nature through sport."
その女々しき根性叩き直してくれる
"I will be waiting for you out on the soccer field after school ends."
放課後サッカー場にて待つ
"Tenshi." How dare she?!
天使だっとーッ
That doesn't make sense. Did she really write that?
ワケがわからん内容だな～
本当にあいつが書いたのか
今の天使はもう前の天使じゃないからな～
The current Tenshi is not the Tenshi we used to know.
With all of 'em all fused, I guess she could've written some stupid-sounding challenge letter like that.
いろんなものが混ざっちまったから
こんな阿呆な挑戦状も書きかねねぇか
こんなバカらしい話つきあってられるか
I'm not taking part in something like that!
I'm bringing this to Yurippe's attention.
ゆりっぺに報告するぞ
I said it's a secret from Yuri, didn't I?
だから　ゆりには内緒だって言っただろ
なぜ
Why is that?
ゆりに言ったらまた物騒な戦いに発展するぜ
If we tell Yuri about this, it'll turn into another war.
ほら　スポーツマンシップに則りって書いてある
Look here. It says a sports match.
今回はスポーツで正々堂々と戦おうって言ってきてじゃん
This time, she's saying we'll be able to fight through sports, fair and square.
それにオレらオトコに向けての挑戦状だぜ
Besides, this is a challenge letter to us guys.
ゆりに言いつけるなんて
Reporting it to Yuri will only sully us further.
それこそオトコの名がすたる
I see his point.
なるほど　言えてるぜ
んじゃ　この五人で行くか
Then let's have just us five take care of this.
Kiss you!
That's what I like to hear!
そう来なくちゃッ
Soccer Field
What's this?
うん？　なんだ
おい　あそこ見ろよ
Hey, look at that.
Someone's there.
誰かいるぞ
It's Yui.
ユイじゃん
What's she doing?
なにしてんだ　あいつ
来やがったか
So you're finally here.
キックオフ
Kick off!
ボールを蹴り始めたぞ
She's dribbling the ball.
You guys ready?!
いくぞ　てめえらぁ
わかった　手紙の主はあいつだ
I get it! It was she who wrote the letter!
きっと　普段から不甲斐ないオレたちに苛立ちを思っていたんだ
She must be pissed off at us since we're always so useless!
それで　こんなマネを
That's why she's doing this!
Protect the goal! We can't lose this game!
よし　ゴールを守れ
この戦い負けられねえ
We men will win!
オレたちオトコが勝つ
I don't really get this,
よくわからんが
but you got me!
わかった
舐めんじゃねえぞ　こら
Don't look down on us!
I kiss you!
Hinata, you're the goalie!
日向　キーパー
You got it!
おいよ
Move out of my way, jackass!
どけーッ！　こんばけ
ふん　下手くそうなドリブルを
What a lousy dribble.
You're full of openings!
隙だらけだ
Prepare yourself!
覚悟
Ow!
わっいたッ
よっしゃ　一人抜き
Okay, one down!
なにごとだ
What happened?
What're you doin', Noda?!
何やってんだ　野田
二人目　こりゃ
Two down!
Ref! That's gotta be a red card, right?!
審判　レッドカードだろう　今の
Safe.
セーフ
どこのだれのつもりだよ
Who are you imitating?
Here I come!
まだまだ行くぞ　てめえら
たのむ　ＴＫ　音無
Stop her, T.K.! Otonashi!
Easy come! Easy go!
We got it!
まかせろ
Here's number three!
三人目
Cut!
チョップ
Way to go!
よしゃ
Here we go!
Sorry!
お　わりぃ
てめえ　どっちの味方だよ
Just whose side are you on?!
ふん　最後は　てめえか
So you're the last one, eh?!
I'll take the goal even if it means killing you.
殺してでもゴールを奪う
Where did your sportsmanship go?!
お前　スポーツマンシップはどこ行った
I don't give a damn!
んなこと知るか
Take this! Super Killer Guillotine Shoot!
覚悟
必殺「殺人ギロチンシュート」
Is she trying to score the goal or trying to kill me?!
オレを殺したいのかゴールを決めたいのか
どっちなのかツッコミどころの多いシュートがきやがった
奇跡だ
It's a miracle!
Hinata!
日向!
入った
It went in.
Yay!
やった
やったやった
Yay! Yay! I outran five people!
五人抜き完成
Impossible.
馬鹿な
オレたちの負けだなんて
We lost?
ユイ一人にだぞ
To make it worse, it was just to Yui.
Scrambled it. Trouble down.
This sucks.
最悪だ
Let's keep this a secret.
絶対内緒にしておこうな
Yeah.
うん
しかし　一度とられてるしキーパーを抜いてないし
She actually lost the ball once,
and she didn't dribble past the goalie...
グダグダだったんだが
But, oh well.
まあ　いいか
よし
Okay.
Let's do this!
じゃ次　やりますか
その前に　どな辺まで飛んだら　ホームランってことにするんだ
Baseball Field
Before we do, how far does the hit need to go to count as a home run?
Over the fence, of course.
そんなの　フェンス越えに決まってんじゃん
まじかよ
Seriously?
とにかく　思いっ切り打ってみろ
Well then, hit it the best you can.
当たった
Yeah! I hit it!
Just hitting it isn't what you need.
あたりゃいいってわけじゃねえからな～
もっとバールをよく見てバットの心で当ててみろよ
Keep your eyes on the ball, and hit it with the sweet spot of the bat.
You're only hitting the top of the ball.
バールの上を叩き過ぎてる
今度は下過ぎ
You're too low, now.
目を瞑っててあたるか
You'll never hit it with your eyes closed!
She's weak.
非力だ
ほら　がんばれ
Hey, keep it up!
そりゃがんばるよ
I am!
One more!
もう一回
あれ
Huh?
You're too tired. You're losing your grip.
ダメだ　お前
疲れて握力が落ちてる
これ以上続けても今日はムダだ
There's no point in continuing today.
You've got a nice big shout, but your hits aren't big at all!
掛け声ばっかりでかくても　当たりはちっともでかくないぞ
まだまだ
I'm not done yet!
That was close!
あ　惜しい
Huh?
あれ
今日はもう暗くて　ボールが見えないな
It's too dark to see the ball now.
またあしただ
We'll try again tomorrow.
What are you two up to?
お前ら　なにやってんの
よっ
Sup.
お前もやるか　本気の野球
You want to play a serious game?
Full swing, eh?
フルスウィングか
最近してねぇや
Haven't done one in a while.
そういうのもイイかもな
Maybe... it wouldn't be such a bad idea.
What's wrong?! You're not following through on your swings at all!
どうした　ぜんぜん触れてねえぞ
大丈夫か
Are you all right?
お前　手を見せてみろ
Show me your hands.
イヤだ
No.
見せろって
I said show me.
無理もねぇか
Naturally, there's no way.
It was impossible to begin with.
所詮無理なんだよ
Just forget about this dream.
もうイイや　この夢
Don't give up...
あきらめんなよ
いろいろありがとうね
Thank you for your help.
Why are you doing all this for me, by the way?
なんでこんなことをしてくれたの
それは
Well...
お前がやりたかったことだろう
You wanted to do this, right?
Keep working until the end!
最後までがんばれよ
ホームランなんて冗談みたいな夢だよ
Hitting a home run for me is like a joke.
ホームランが打てなくても
Even if I couldn't hit a home run, I was able to move around so much, so that was enough.
こんなにいっぱいカラダ動かせたんだから
もう十分だよ
毎日部活みたいで楽しかったな
Every day felt like a club activity. It was fun!
言ったでしょう
I told you how I couldn't move, right?
アタシ　カラダ動かせなかったから　だから　すげえ楽しかった
So really, this was a lot of fun!
じゃあ　もう全部叶ったのか
Then, has everything been granted for you?
"Granted"? What do you mean?
叶う？なにが
I mean, did you get to do everything you wanted to do when you were alive?
その、カラダが動かせなかったときにしたかったコト
There's one more thing.
もう一個あるよ
なに
What is it?
結婚
To get married.
オンナの究極の幸せ
A girl's ultimate happiness.
でも　家事も洗濯もできない
But I couldn't do any household chores.
Worse yet, I couldn't do anything alone.
それどころか　ひとりじゃ何にもできない
I was such dead weight.
迷惑ばかりかけてるこんなお荷物
だれが貰ってくれるかな
I wonder who would ever marry me.
神様ってひどいよね
God is so mean.
アタシのシアワセ　全部奪っていったんだ
He took... all my happiness away...
そんなこと　ない
That's not true.
In that case, Senpai... would you marry me?
じゃ先輩
アタシと結婚してくれますか
That's...
それは
I'd marry you!
オレがしてやんよ
日向
Hinata.
オレが結婚してやんよ
I'd marry you.
これがオレの本気だ
I mean it... really.
そんな
But... you don't know who I really am.
先輩がホントのアタシを知らないもん
Whenever we met, all we did was argue,
kao wo awashitara kenka shite bakari
顔を合わしたら喧嘩してばかり
顔を合わせたら喧嘩した２人
唄：LiSA
一番の宝物
現実が、生きてたときのお前がどんなでも
However you might have been when you were alive, I'd marry you!
オレが結婚してやんよ
But even those times are good memories.
sore mo ii omoide datta
それもいい思い出だった
もしお前がどんなハンデを抱えてでも
No matter what kind of handicap you might have had.
ユイ歩けないよ
I can't walk, you know. I can't get up, either.
立てないよ
You were the one who taught me, and I'm not afraid any more,
kimi ga oshietekuretanda mou kowakunai
きみが教えてくれたんだ　もう恐くない
どんなハンデでもっつったろう
I said no matter what kind of handicap, didn't I?!
きみが教えてくれたんだ
歩けなくても　立てなくても
Even if you can't walk or get up or have kids...
もう怖くない
もし子どもが産めなくても
That no matter what inconvenience comes my way, I can attain happiness.
donna fujiyuu demo shiawase ha tsukameru dakara
どんな不自由でも幸せは掴める　だから
どんな不自由でも
Even so, I'd still marry you!
それでも　オレはお前と結婚してやんよ
幸せは掴める
ずっとずっと傍にいてやんよ
I'd always be with you.
だから…
ここで出会ったお前はユイの偽物じゃない
The person I came to know in this world isn't a fake Yui.
ユイだ
It's you.
どこで出会っていたとしても
No matter where I might have met you,
I'm sure I'd have come to love you.
I'll move on alone if I have to, even if it's painful,
hitori demo yuku yo tatoe tsurakutemo
ひとりでもゆくよ　例え辛くても
一人でも行くよ
オレはスキになっていたはずだ
また６０億分の１の確率で出会えたら
例え辛くても
If we meet again, with even a one in six billion chance, and even if you couldn't move again,
君と見た夢は
And I'll definitely take the dream I had with you along.
kimi to mita yume ha kanarazu motteku yo
きみと見た夢は　必ず持ってくよ
そんときもまた　お前が動けないカラダだったとしても
必ず持っていくよ
お前と結婚してやんよ
I'd still marry you.
君とが良かった
Being with you was what I wanted; you and no one else,
kimi to ga yokatta hoka no dare demo nai
きみとがよかった　ほかの誰でもない
出会えないよ
We'd never meet up with each other. I'd always be sleeping at home.
ユイ　家で寝たきりだもん
他の誰でもない
オレは野球やってるからさ
Well, I'd be playing baseball.
でもね　駄目だった
But when I opened my eyes, you were nowhere to be found.
demo mezameta asa kimi ha inainda ne
でも目覚めた朝　きみは居ないんだね
So I'll end up breaking one of your windows with a ball I've hit.
ある日　お前んちの窓をバリンと打ったまで割っちまうんだ
君はいないなんだね
それをとりに行くとさ　お前がいるんだ
When I go to fetch that ball, you'd be there.
それが出会い
That's how we'd meet.
話するとさ　気が合ってさ
We'd start talking, and find that we get along, so I'd start visiting you every day.
いつしか毎日通うようになる
I'd start taking care of you, as well.
介護も始める
そういうのはどうだ
How does that sound?
I like that.
うん
I can keep on playing forever, that's the feeling I got,
zutto asondereru sonna ki ga shiteta
ずっと遊んでれる　そんな気がしてた
Hey, when that happens,
ねえ　そんときはさ
ずっと遊んでいる そんな気がしてた
アタシをいつも一人でさがんばって介護してくれた
my mum will be there, always taking care of me.
アタシのお母さん楽にしてあげてね
気がしていただけ
I understood just from watching you do the same.
ki ga shiteita dake wakatteru
気がしていただけ　わかってる
Make sure you take the weight off of her.
分かって
まかせろ
Count on it.
I'll no longer regret the fact that I was born,
umaretekita koto mou koukai ha shinai
生まれてきたこともう後悔はしない
よかった
I'm glad.
祭りの後みたい
Like the end of a festival; I feel lonely, but it's time to get going.
matsuri no ato mitai samishii kedo sorosoro ikou
祭りの後みたい　寂しいけどそろそろ行こう
寂しいけど　そろそろ行こう
どこまでも行くよ ここで知ったこと
I'll go as far as I have to, I learned that fact right here,
doko made mo yuku yo koko de shitta koto
どこまでもゆくよ　ここで知ったこと
I'll show you that I can grant my dream of happiness.
shiawase to iu yume wo kanaetemiseru yo
幸せという夢を叶えてみせるよ
Even if we're separated, no matter the distance,
kimi to hanaretemo donna ni tookunattemo
きみと離れても　どんなに遠くなっても
君と離れても
どんなに遠くなっても
When the new morning breaks, I'll go on living.
atarashii asa ni atashi ha ikiru yo
新しい朝に　あたしは生きるよ
新しい朝に私は生きるよ
Flowing in and out, time weaves its way,
megutte nagarete toki ha utsuroida
巡って流れて　時は移ろいだ
巡って流れて 時はうつろいだ
Was that all right?
よかったのか
I can't even remember what's happened to me any more.
mou nani ga atta ka omoidasenai kedo
もう何があったか　思い出せないけど
もう何があったか 思い出せないけど
よかったさ
Sure it was.
お前は　これからどうする
What are you going to do now?
目を閉じてみれば 誰かの笑い声
If I try closing my eyes, I hear the sound of someone laughing,
me wo tojitemireba dareka no waraigoe
目を閉じてみれば　誰かの笑い声
オレも最後まで付き合うさ
I'll stick around until the end.
まだまだ心配なやつらが残ってるからな
There are still a bunch of people left that worry me.
Somehow, right now, that seems like my greatest treasure.
naze ka sore ga ima ichiban no takaramono
なぜかそれが今一番の宝物
何故かそれが今　一番の宝物
そうか
I see.
What did I just kill?
今　俺は何を斬ったんだ
カゲ？
A shadow?
Give a better explanation.
もうちょっとちゃんと説明してよ
It can only be described as a shadow.
影としか説明できません
今駆け付けた野田さんが倒したところです
Noda-san just exterminated it.
Ooyama-san was in danger.
大山さん一人で危ないところでした
危ないって
"Was in danger"?
From what?
何が
Next Episode Preview
Something strange is starting to happen in this world.
Did you do something again?!
Who'd have thought he'd drop his glasses...
Is this some sort of nightmare?
I tried to save him, too!
I don't need help!
This is too much of an irregularity...
Something's invading me, Otonashi-san!
Dancing in the shadow!
It'd be better gettin' erased by Tenshi.
You'll disappear!
Damn it!
What's going on?
Yurippe!
I'll be waiting!
Well, we'll meet again if we can.